Saim Minhas

21 Grasmere Way MK2 3DZ Mobile: 07814 760 367

Email: saim_sajid@hotmail.com linkedin.com/in/saim-minhas-b7400a60

PERSONAL PROFILE

An experienced IT specialist having both relevant qualifications as well as vast practical experience obtained over the past 14 years. Excellent communication and leadership skills to successfully achieve company objectives. Keen to learn new skills to enhance career prospects especially in the Cloud sector. In depth knowledge of Cloud Computing including Azure. Currently studying Microsoft Azure Architect Technologies course to progress towards Azure Solutions Architect Expert. Seeking an opportunity in either a current or Cloud based role where existing and potential skills are utilised to the fullest extent.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Global Support Services Representative (Nordson Dage) - contract

Oct 2018 - Present

- Working with a Global Service Desk Support Team in Aylesbury
- Processing tickets using Service Now
- Following the company's SLA
- Managing user details in O365 and AD
- Processing password reset/unlock for network and SAP
- Troubleshooting mobile devices i.e. iPads, Android and laptops
- · Remotely accessing client machines through TeamViewer
- Troubleshooting Network Printers either remotely or physically
- Providing logon help with extranet, intranet and share point
- Staying current with system information, changes and updates.
- Identify and escalate situations requiring urgent attention.
- Responding to requests for technical assistance in person, via phone, electronically
- Using SCCM to manage network machines i.e. remote troubleshooting, deploying updates
- Logging all help desk interactions and providing initial documentation for knowledge article creation.

1st Line Service Desk and Desktop Support (HCL) - contract

May 2018 - Oct 2018

- Working with a Global Service Desk Support Team in Cambridge providing both 1st and 2nd line support
- · Supporting users around the world including US, Canada, SA, Singapore and Australia
- Generating tickets using Service Now
- Providing technical assistance via chat, email, or phone
- Writing, editing, and updating knowledge-based articles for various technical scenarios
- Using the built-in reports feature of Service-now to analyse common complaints and issues
- Using SCCM to manage network machines i.e. remote troubleshooting, deploying updates
- Use of Mobile Iron to manage mobile devices i.e. iPads, Android and laptops
- Using AD Manager Plus to manage Active Directory
- Remotely accessing client machines through ISLOnline or Bomgar to fix technical issues
- Providing top class customer service and staying calm under pressure
- Generating Reports using built-in feature of Service-now
- Escalating issues to L2 or L3 when required
- Providing top class customer service and staying calm under pressure
- Helping other team members to reduce work load during busy hours

Freelance IT Technician (Self Employed part-time)

Oct 2004 - April 2018

- Installing and configuring appropriate software and operating system according to specifications
- Performing Microsoft recommended troubleshooting techniques to diagnose issues
- Providing a high-level service for customers, by being attentive and pro-active

- Developing different kinds of softwares for various clients i.e. financial, payroll, stock
- Using Visual Basic as the front end and Sql Server as back end
- Implementing different phases of the software development life cycle

IT SKILLS

Cloud Environment

Azure, Office 365 Suite, AADP, DirSync, SharePoint Online, IaaS, PaaS, Azure AD Connect, AWS

Azure Expertise

Managing Accounts and Subscriptions, Implementing and Managing Storage, Deploying and Managing Virtual Machines, Configuring and Managing Virtual Networks

OS and Server Tools

Server 2008, 2008 R2, Server 2012, Windows 10, 7, XP and Vista

Networking (LAN/WAN)

TCP/IP, Cisco Any Connect, DHCP, DNS, Direct Access, Cache modes, Cisco Switches and Routers using Packet Tracer

Active Directory

AD, AD DS, Server Manager, ADFS, AD Manager Plus (creating, updating and deleting both user accounts and Group Policies including managing OUs)

Scripting

PowerShell, Java Scripting, Html

Programming languages

C++ and Visual Basic

System troubleshooting

Data Collector Sets, Windows Recovery Environment, Event Viewer, Resource Monitor, Performance Monitor, Command prompt commands

Enterprise Security

ReFS, EFS, NTFS, Internet Security, Windows Defender, WSUS, NAP, AppLocker, BitLocker

Database

Oracle, Sql Server, FoxPro, Microsoft Access

Desktop Virtualization

VMware Workstation Pro and Hyper-v

Others

SCCM 1706, WebEx Meeting Centre, Secret Server 7.9, Messages labs through Symantec Cloud, Accellion, DinoPass, Bell Total Connect Portal, Asset Manager, Citrix Receiver and Compass (Share Point Server 2007), Z-Scaler, Cisco Any Connect (ASA 5510), Okta

- Knowledge and understanding of: ITIL, EPoS Systems (software/hardware and peripheral devices) and Remedy Call Management System
- Experience of managing IoT assets and installations through Asset Manager

EDUCATION & TRAINING

- Microsoft Azure Architect Technologies AZ-300 (Currently doing a self-study)
- Studied Microsoft Azure Administrator AZ-103
- MCSA Server Admin Course (360 GSP College) Sep 2016 Sep 2017
- MA in Digital Media Design Sep (Glasgow Caledonian University) 2005 Sep 2006
- Bachelor in Computer Science (Hons) Sep 1999 Sep 2002

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

- Customer Service skills Meeting customer needs and achieving targets and ensuring customers are fully satisfied. i.e. software development.
- **Communicating and people skills** Communicating with all levels of people throughout my working career. i.e. managers, team leaders etc.
- **Team skills** Providing the upmost technical support during various roles and ensuring that everyone in the team is kept motivated and included. i.e. Computer Programmer, Software Developer, Service Desk Analyst.